Benjamin Banwart

Fort Scott, Kansas

Benjibanwart@gmail.com | (620)404-2094 | linkedin.com/in/benjamin-banwart-490736224/ | https://github.com/BenjaminBanwart | benjaminbanwart.github.io/Personal_Portfolio/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Software Engineer with experience in full-stack web development including front-end, back-end, and testing. Currently attending a software engineering bootcamp with KSU. Most efficient when working and collaborating with others. Avid lifetime learner and passionate about exceptional visual design and functionality.

EDUCATION

Kansas State University

Manhattan, KS

Software Development Professional Certificate

Graduate in July of 2022

Courses: Front-End Development, UI-UX, Back-End Development and API's, React-Redux

SKILLS PROFILE

Certification: Software Engineer

Development Technologies: JavaScript, CSS, HTML, GitHub, C#, Jinja, Git, React, Redux, NodeJS, Express, Bootstrap,

Mongoose, macOS, Linux **Databases:** MongoDB

Security:

Deployment Tools: GitHub Pages, Heroku

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

REST-Rant March 2022

- Created a full-stack application that allows users to review restaurants.
- The app is hosted on Heroku and uses MongoDB as a database.
- Development technologies include JavaScript, Bootstrap, MongoDB, Express, NodeJS, JSX, and express-react-views.

Books API March 2022

- Created a JavaScript API for books.
- Users can send requests, use all CRUD operations, and view responses rendered as JSON in the browser.
- API is hosted on Heroku and uses MongoDB as a database.

NASA API Image Implementation

February 2022

- Created a web page that utilizes the NASA APOD API, JavaScript, and minimalist CSS styling.
- The page updates daily with a new image of space and a description of said image along with the title, author, and copyrights.

Pokemon_Battle_Game

January 2022–February 2022

- Created a fully-functional browser Pokemon battle game using raw HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- The JavaScript logic allows for a user to choose his or her party of Pokemon and then battle against a computer player until the user wins or loses.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Hairbow Center, Fort Scott, KS

February 2020–Present

Catalog Listing Assistant

- List highly detailed and niche products on Etsy
- Communicate regularly with the product analyst and the sales department in creating the varying products with details that are oriented for sales optimization

Hairbow Center, Fort Scott, KS

April 2014–February 2020

Warehouse Laborer

- Worked in product production and conversion
- Converted large product units to multiple small product units while operating a machine
- Kept shelves saturated with product for pickers
- Troubleshooted inventory errors using online sku-based inventory management system and communication with co-workers